<?xml version="1.0" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="brochures.css" ?><brochures><table-of-contents/>           <factsheet id="f1"><category>EnterTheGrid - The world's largest database on Grid computing</category><title>A business intelligence tool for the Grid</title><introduction><paragraph>            Grid computing is a fast moving,  dynamic area. The Grid market  will grow in  double or even triple numbers in the coming years.  New companies are formed each month; new products are released, projects initiated, funding programmes announced. To stay in this highly competitive market you need information on what is happening. To stay ahead of the competition, find new opportunities, and identify threats, you need detailed and up to date information. This is where EnterTheGrid helps you. We have the largest database on Grid computing in the world. We update it on a daily basis and provide tools to access and analysis the Grid market. The EnterTheGrid database service is available for a yearly subscription fee. </paragraph>          </introduction><background><paragraph>To stay up-to-date with the dynamic Grid market today, you need to buy market analysis reports. These are updated only once a year and  expensive. So you further need to go to several conferences and  browse  the web. You need to combine all the information and that just to keep up-to-date. With EnterTheGrid you do not need to pay for expensive marketing studies: you make your own. With EnterTheGrid you do no have to spend time on conferences gathering information: you have it all available with a click of the mouse. With EnterTheGrid you do not need to spend time searching the web for Grid information: it is all accessible from one place. A subscription to EnterTheGrid saves you time and money and, most importantly, gives you the confidence you did not miss anything.    </paragraph><paragraph>           EnterTheGrid is the largest catalogue of Grid related information in the world. It contains information on all the companies,  projects and products in the Grid market. It also  contains links to other information sources, that are seamlessly available.</paragraph>     <paragraph><figure      id="etg-plaatje.jpg"     description="EnterTheGrid combines information from own research with information from other information sources. This provides the largest source of Grid computing information in the world"  /></paragraph>         <paragraph>As the Grid moves more from research into main stream, the EnterTheGrid catalogue will move along with it, providing more information on industrial and commercial uses. Today, for instance, EnterTheGrid not only lists companies active in computational Grid, but also lists companies active in networking and storage providing you with a complete overview.</paragraph><paragraph>How can you benefit from access to all this  information?   To summarise:         <unordered-list>            <list-item>You have an up to date view of the state of Grid computing. New products, projects, and companies are added as soon as information is available.</list-item>            <list-item>See where items fit in. Which companies are active in your specific area? Which companies are potential partners or competitors? </list-item>            <list-item>Which products are there that implement a specific standard. Is there room to enter with a new product? </list-item>            <list-item>By having access to the database itself, you can do your own analysis which can give you the advantage you need to stay competitive in the Grid market.</list-item>            </unordered-list>            </paragraph> <paragraph>           What do you get for an EnterTheGrid subscription? EnterTheGrid provides you with the following  business intelligence services:           <unordered-list>           <list-item>Access to the aggregate database: the EnterTheGrid database and the registry.  </list-item>           <list-item>Analysis tools to make own analysis of the combined data. This is in addition to the general search tools available to everyone through the public EnterTheGrid web site.</list-item>           <list-item>Regular reports on the state of the Grid, written by Primeur/EnterTheGrid editors</list-item>           <list-item>Support for linking the information to company-internal databases.</list-item>           </unordered-list>           </paragraph>           <paragraph>The database is accessible in XML-format. You can use your own XML-tools or the ones provided by Primeur/EnterTheGrid to access it.</paragraph>                     <paragraph>You can find examples of what can be  done with the information on the EnterTheGrid.com web site:            <unordered-list>            <list-item>Use the "Search taxonomy" to list products according a specific taxonomy (classification scheme). Background information can be found in          <a href="http://EnterTheGrid.com/vmp/articles/EnterTheGrid/AE-PR-08-02-72.html"   xlink:type="simple"    xlink:show="new"   xlink:href="http://EnterTheGrid.com/vmp/articles/EnterTheGrid/AE-PR-08-02-72.html"   xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >EnterTheGrid adds Knowledge Management to world's largest Grid catalogue</a>         </list-item>         <list-item>For an example of combining information from several sources: <linkto href="http://EnterTheGrid.com/vmp/articles/EnterTheGrid/AE-PR-09-02-83.html"   xlink:type="simple"    xlink:show="new"   xlink:href="http://EnterTheGrid.com/vmp/articles/EnterTheGrid/AE-PR-09-02-83.html"   xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" >   Information from TOP500, EnterTheGrid used to enrich supercomputer overview report</linkto>     </list-item>           </unordered-list>            </paragraph>            <paragraph>There is also a public web-site called EnterTheGrid.com. This <em>light version</em> also contains a lot of information. But when you take a subscription, you will, however, get much more:<unordered-list><list-item>You get access  to the database. The public web site just contains HTML pages.</list-item><list-item>You access  to more information and more information sources.</list-item><list-item>You get more search, list and exploration tools.</list-item><list-item>You get four additional reports a year. </list-item></unordered-list></paragraph><paragraph>Tentative 2003 reports:<unordered-list><list-item>February: Software tools for the Grid - What is available, what can one expect</list-item><list-item>June:  Computational Grids and the TOP500 list of world's most powerful supercomputers</list-item><list-item>October: The companies active in the Grid.</list-item><list-item>December: Evaluation of the success of large Grid funding efforts</list-item></unordered-list></paragraph>            <paragraph>These services are available for use within your company for  a yearly subscription fee. We start with the service on January 1, 2003. In the mean time it is in beta-test with selected customers. </paragraph>     </background><product-spec><paragraph>A subscription to the EnterTheGrid database service features:<unordered-list><list-item>One year access to the full XML-database for in-company use</list-item><list-item>A set of tools for analysing the database</list-item><list-item>Up to four reports with information on Grid computing and the use of the database </list-item><list-item>Assistance with linking the EnterTheGrid database to in-company databases</list-item></unordered-list></paragraph><paragraph>Other services from Primeur/EnterTheGrid include our leading Primeur/EnterTheGrid news magazine, Grid/HPC analyst and editorial services.</paragraph></product-spec><information><addresses><address><address-line>Primeur/EnterTheGrid</address-line><address-line>A service of Genias Benelux bv</address-line><address-line>mailto:primeur@hoise.com</address-line><address-line>http://EnterTheGrid.com</address-line></address><address><address-line>Genias Benelux bv</address-line><address-line>James Stewartstraat 248</address-line><address-line>1325 JN Almere</address-line><address-line>The Netherlands</address-line><address-line>tel: +31 36 5373867</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@genias.nl</address-line></address> <!--<address><address-line>United Kingdom contact</address-line><address-line>HiPerCom Consultants Ltd.</address-line><address-line>10 Western Road</address-line><address-line>London N2 9HX</address-line><address-line>United Kingdom</address-line><address-line>Tel/Fax: +44 (0)208 444 3245</address-line></address><address-line>Italy contact</address-line><address-line>HiPerCom Consultants Ltd.</address-line><address-line>10 Western Road</address-line><address-line>London N2 9HX</address-line><address-line>United Kingdom</address-line><address-line>Tel/Fax: +44 (0)208 444 3245</address-line></address><address-line>Germany contact</address-line><address-line>HiPerCom Consultants Ltd.</address-line><address-line>10 Western Road</address-line><address-line>London N2 9HX</address-line><address-line>United Kingdom</address-line><address-line>Tel/Fax: +44 (0)208 444 3245</address-line></address><address><address-line>In Switzerland contact:</address-line><address-line>Decker Consulting GmbH</address-line><address-line>Birkenstrasse 49</address-line><address-line>CH-6343 Rotkreuz  SWITZERLAND</address-line><address-line>Tel: +41 (41) 790-9080</address-line><address-line>decker@mit-solutions.com</address-line></address><address />--></addresses></information><date>2002-11-21</date><author>Ad Emmen, Genias</author></factsheet><factsheet id="f2"><category>GridSET - VR simulator based training courses</category><title>Training course for lumbar punction procedure </title><introduction>This GridSET product is designed to shorten the training time for medical students practising the lumbar puncture procedure. Embedded within a full training course is a Virtual Reality based simulator, allowing the trainee to improve his skills by providing a tool to acquire 3-D knowledge of the surgery area. </introduction><background>    <paragraph>Lumbar punctures are commonly carried out on patients with neurological conditions as an aid to diagnosis and as a therapeutic procedure (e.g. benign intracranial hypertension). They are performed between the lumbar vertebral spaces, usually at the L4/L5 level, although they can be done at a higher level. A lumbar puncture It is a complex clinical skill which requires the clinician to precisely correlate a detailed mental map of hidden 3D anatomy with tactile feedback from the spinal needle as it is being inserted. </paragraph><figure id="demo-33"  /><paragraph>The <em>GridSET - VR simulator based training course for lumbar punction</em> aims at helping the trainee to become         familiar with the  steps of a lumbar punction.</paragraph><paragraph>In comparison to other training approaches, GridSET offers the unique possibility to interact with a 3-D simulated model. The model can be viewed from all sides and be made transparent. The procedure can be  performed and an objective evaluation of the quality of the surgery is given to the trainee. </paragraph><paragraph>At the end of  this GridSET course, the trainee will be capable to:<unordered-list>         <list-item>Explain the procedure to the patient</list-item>         <list-item>Position the patient correctly on the bed </list-item>         <list-item>Identify and mark L3-4 or L4-5 Inter-vertebral space  </list-item>         <list-item>Determine the orientation of the needle based on anatomical landmarks and patient's position </list-item>         <list-item>Insert the spinal needle accurately </list-item>         <list-item>Understand and describe the post-needle insertion steps (measuring CSF pressure, sample collection, patient recovery) </list-item>       </unordered-list>   </paragraph><paragraph>In the end the trainee will have the appropriate skills to perform the initial steps of  a lumbar punction.</paragraph><paragraph>The GridSET lumbar punction training course is divided into four parts:<unordered-list>         <list-item>The theoretical basis of the lumbar punction approach</list-item>         <list-item>Video clips</list-item>         <list-item>Practice on the simulation</list-item>         <list-item>Multiple-choice questionnaire</list-item>       </unordered-list></paragraph></background><product-spec><paragraph> A GridSET Integrated training course  course is a complete training course that can be used in a web based class-environment.It contains:<figure id="demo-64"  /><unordered-list><list-item>A complete training course for lumbar puncture, with theory, examples, multiple choice questions and VR based simulator</list-item><list-item>GridSET evaluation module: allowing students to assess their skills. Can also be used in examination mode</list-item><list-item>GridSET conference server: allows the teacher and students to collaboratively view and work on the same surgery simulator. Comes with communication possibilities between participants.</list-item><list-item>GridSET training server: a container to run one or more GridSET training courses. </list-item><list-item>License for a maximum of 50 students</list-item></unordered-list>  </paragraph></product-spec><system-requirements>  <paragraph>For the server: Windows NT or Unix. For the students (client side): Windows system with Explorer 5.5. All additional software is either packed with the training server, or can be acquired over the web. </paragraph></system-requirements><information><addresses><address><address-line>Austria</address-line><address-line>UMA Information Technology AG</address-line><address-line>Donau City Str 1</address-line><address-line>A-1220 Vienna</address-line><address-line>tel: +43 1 526 2967 701</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@uma.nl</address-line></address><address><address-line>Belgium</address-line><address-line>Space Applications Services</address-line><address-line>Leuvensesteenweg 325</address-line><address-line>B-1932 Zaventem</address-line><address-line>tel: +32 2 7215484</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@spaceapplications.com</address-line></address><address><address-line>The Netherlands</address-line><address-line>Genias Benelux bv</address-line><address-line>James Stewartstraat 248</address-line><address-line>1325 JN Almere</address-line><address-line>tel: +31 36 5373867</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@genias.nl</address-line></address><address><address-line>Greece</address-line><address-line>IDEC S.A.</address-line><address-line>96 Iroon Polytechniou Str.</address-line><address-line>185 36 Piraeus</address-line><address-line>tel: +30 1 04286227</address-line><address-line>mailto: info@idec.gr</address-line></address></addresses></information><date>2002-07-02</date><author>Fernando Bello, Imperial College School of Medicine</author><author>Ad Emmen, Genias</author></factsheet><!-- =============================================================== --><!-- =============================================================== --><factsheet id="f3"><category>GridSET - VR simulator based training courses</category><title>Training course for laparoscopic surgery</title><introduction>This GridSET product is designed to shorten the training time for surgery students practising the laparoscopic  procedure. Embedded within a full training course is a Virtual Reality based simulator, allowing the trainee to improve his skills by providing a tool to acquire 3-D knowledge of the surgery area.</introduction><background>    <paragraph>Laparoscopic surgery has gained a world-wide acceptance         in recent years and this acceptance has necessitated the education of         surgeons on these new laparoscopic techniques. Laparoscopic cholecystectomy         is the most frequently laparoscopic operation performed and constitutes         the basis of all the educational programmes on laparoscopic techniques.         This operation and all the other laparoscopic operations begin with the         same basic steps.</paragraph><figure id="demo-40"  /><paragraph>The <em>GridSET - VR simulator based training coursesTraining course for laparoscopic  surgery</em> aims at helping the trainee to become         familiar with the initial steps of laparoscopic surgery, which are common         in all laparoscopic operations, laparoscopic cholecystectomy being the         prototype.</paragraph><paragraph>Unique, in comparison to other training approaches, is the possibility to interact with a 3-D simulated model. The model can be viewed from all sides and be made transparent. The procedure can be performed and an objective evaluation of the quality of the surgery is given to the trainee.</paragraph><paragraph>At the end of this GridSET course, the trainee will be capable to:<unordered-list>         <list-item>Choose the appropriate tool</list-item>         <list-item>Choose the correct position for insertion of the Veress           needle and the trocars</list-item>         <list-item>Insert the Veress needle and the trocars accurately</list-item>         <list-item>Establish an adequate pneumoperitoneum</list-item>       </unordered-list>   </paragraph><paragraph>In the end the trainee will have the appropriate skills to perform the initial steps of  a laparoscopy  operation.</paragraph><paragraph>The GridSET laparoscopy  surgery training course  is divided into four parts:<unordered-list>         <list-item>The theoretical basis of the laparoscopic approach</list-item>         <list-item>Video clips</list-item>         <list-item>Practice on the simulator</list-item>         <list-item>Practice with multiple-choice questions.</list-item>       </unordered-list></paragraph></background><product-spec><paragraph> A GridSET Integrated training course   is a complete training course that can be used in a web based class-environment.It contains:<unordered-list><list-item>A complete training course for laparoscopic surgery, with theory, examples, multiple choice questions and VR based simulator</list-item><list-item>GridSET evaluation module: allowing students to assess their skills. Can also be used in examination mode</list-item><list-item>GridSET conference server: allows the teacher and students to collaboratively view and work on the same surgery simulator. Comes with communication possibilities between participants.</list-item><list-item>GridSET training server: a container to run one or more GridSET training courses. </list-item><list-item>License for a maximum of 50 students</list-item></unordered-list>  </paragraph><figure id="demo-42"  /></product-spec><system-requirements>  <paragraph>System requirements: For the server: Windows NT or Unix. For the students (client side): Windows system with Explorer 5.5. All additional software is either packed with the training server, or can be acquired over the web. </paragraph></system-requirements><information><addresses><address><address-line>Austria</address-line><address-line>UMA Information Technology AG</address-line><address-line>Donau City Str 1</address-line><address-line>A-1220 Vienna</address-line><address-line>tel: +43 1 526 2967 701</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@uma.nl</address-line></address><address><address-line>Belgium</address-line><address-line>Space Applications Services</address-line><address-line>Leuvensesteenweg 325</address-line><address-line>B-1932 Zaventem</address-line><address-line>tel: +32 2 7215484</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@spaceapplications.com</address-line></address><address><address-line>The Netherlands</address-line><address-line>Genias Benelux bv</address-line><address-line>James Stewartstraat 248</address-line><address-line>1325 JN Almere</address-line><address-line>tel: +31 36 5373867</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@genias.nl</address-line></address><address><address-line>Greece</address-line><address-line>IDEC S.A.</address-line><address-line>96 Iroon Polytechniou Str.</address-line><address-line>185 36 Piraeus</address-line><address-line>tel: +30 1 04286227</address-line><address-line>mailto: info@idec.gr</address-line></address></addresses></information><date>2002-07-09</date><author>Ad Emmen, Genias</author></factsheet><!-- =============================================================== --><!-- =============================================================== --><factsheet id="f4"><category>GridSET - VR simulator based training courses</category><title>Training course for ventricular catheterisation surgery</title><introduction>This GridSET product is designed to shorten the training time for surgery students practising the ventricular catheterisation procedure. Embedded within a  full training course is an Virtual Reality based simulator, allowing the trainee to improve his skills by providing a tool to acquire 3-D knowledge of the surgery area.</introduction><background><paragraph>Ventricular catheterisation is a task performed frequently in neurosurgery, either as a complete procedure in its own right or as part of a procedure to provide further ventricular access.</paragraph><paragraph>Neurosurgical trainees need to acquire this skill early in their training, and they need to develop a 3-D appreciation of the brain and its internal structures.</paragraph><paragraph>The computer simulation presented here  allowsrepeated performance of the task remote from the patient.</paragraph><figure id="demo-34"  /><paragraph>The <em>GridSET - VR simulator basedtraining course for ventricular catheterisation surgery</em> aims at helping the trainee to become familiar with the all steps of ventricular catheterisation.</paragraph><paragraph>Unique, in comparison to other training approaches, is the possibility to interact with a 3-D simulated model. The model can be viewed from all sides and be made transparent. The procedure can be performed and an objective evaluation of the quality of the surgery is given to the trainee.</paragraph><paragraph>At the end of  this GridSET course, the trainee will be capable to:<unordered-list><list-item>Choose the correct position of the head</list-item><list-item>Choose the correct entry point for the catheter</list-item><list-item>Determine the trajectory</list-item><list-item>Insert the ventricular catheter accurately</list-item></unordered-list></paragraph><paragraph>After finishing this GridSET  based training course,  the trainee will have the appropriate skills to perform the initial steps of ventricular catheterisation operation. </paragraph><paragraph>&#160;</paragraph></background><product-spec><paragraph>The GridSET ventricular catheterisation surgery training course is divided into four parts:<unordered-list><list-item>The theoretical basis of the neurosurgical approach</list-item><list-item>Practice on the simulators</list-item><list-item>Practice with multiple-choice questions.</list-item><list-item>License for a maximum of 50 students</list-item></unordered-list>  </paragraph>  <figure id="demo-65"  /></product-spec><system-requirements>  <paragraph>System requirements: For the server: Windows NT or Unix. For the students (client side): Windows system with Explorer 5.5. All additional software is either packed with the training server, or can be acquired over the web. </paragraph></system-requirements><information><addresses><address><address-line>Austria</address-line><address-line>UMA Information Technology AG</address-line><address-line>Donau City Str 1</address-line><address-line>A-1220 Vienna</address-line><address-line>tel: +43 1 526 2967 701</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@uma.nl</address-line></address><address><address-line>Belgium</address-line><address-line>Space Applications Services</address-line><address-line>Leuvensesteenweg 325</address-line><address-line>B-1932 Zaventem</address-line><address-line>tel: +32 2 7215484</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@spaceapplications.com</address-line></address><address><address-line>The Netherlands</address-line><address-line>Genias Benelux bv</address-line><address-line>James Stewartstraat 248</address-line><address-line>1325 JN Almere</address-line><address-line>tel: +31 36 5373867</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@genias.nl</address-line></address><address><address-line>Greece</address-line><address-line>IDEC S.A.</address-line><address-line>96 Iroon Polytechniou Str.</address-line><address-line>185 36 Piraeus</address-line><address-line>tel: +30 1 04286227</address-line><address-line>mailto: info@idec.gr</address-line></address></addresses></information><date>2002-05-01</date><author>Ad Emmen, Genias</author></factsheet><!-- =============================================================== --><!-- =============================================================== --><factsheet id="f5"><category>Using knowledge to create knowledge</category><title>GridSET Exchange Developers Kit for Knowledge Management</title><introduction>"Finding no matter what is bad searching", as the poet spoke. Advanced searching and topic-aimed finding have become important features in our information society. To know exactly what you are looking for and be able to find this in a fast and accurate way at the time you need it, requires the availability of a fine-tuned tool. GridSET Exchange in this regard has everything in store to match the bold expectations of a demanding user in the field of knowledge management.</introduction><background><paragraph>Just imagine you are not allowed to enter your favourite supermarket. The only thing you can do is say what you want to buy using a few key words. You would buy less, forget to bring home more, and never get the idea to buy yourself a new product. You are used to apply the knowledge you possess of the different departments in your supermarket to shop in a faster and better way and to acquire some inspiring ideas for new products. </paragraph><paragraph>On the Internet we are not that far yet. A search window on the site in most cases is often the only way to use the knowledge you already have. Unfortunately, you have to know what you are looking for. </paragraph> <figure       id="ex1.jpg"       description="The knowledge consumer can classify the collection of items as well , according to the available classification schemes. Classification definitions are on the lines with dots. The items in the collection have been underlined."       repository="../../repository" /> <paragraph>"GridSET Exchange Developer's Kit" is a next generation XML-tool allowing classification of knowledge items by means of classification schemes in which knowledge has already been pre-recorded. The supermarket departments for example can be defined in a classification scheme. The person responsible for the input of knowledge items can use his own version of the classification scheme. The information user can handle another one. It is just like entering a new supermarket where the staff has changed the product divisions according to the place they have in your old familiar store! </paragraph><paragraph>The most important asset of GridSET Exchange is that you can associate knowledge items to one another and show them accordingly. This is one step further than current search engines on most web sites can offer. GridSET Exchange can be entirely configured, on the input side and as far as the embedding is concerned for knowledge consumers into a web site for example. </paragraph><paragraph>You can introduce and add your personalised classification schemes featuring the knowledge in your professional domain. </paragraph><paragraph>In education, a tool like GridSET Exchange stimulates the collaboration between students to gather and classify knowledge. Writing papers and creating projects becomes a lot easier using classified information. Since two know more than one, the project acquires more depth because the GridSET Exchange system allows the accessibility of knowledge, which has been entered into the tool by several persons with different points of interest, from a variety of angles. </paragraph><paragraph>Are you managing your own company or do you work in a firm supported by a host of teleworkers? GridSET Exchange  is then an ideal instrument to spread your knowledge via the Internet and showcase the information and tools available in the company for your colleagues working at a distance. They can run through the repository and program the catalogue according to their specific needs to get the structured and classified information which they require to do their jobs efficiently. </paragraph><paragraph>Knowledge empowers. Thus sounded the call at the dawn of the era which gave birth to the current telecommunications and information networking. This axiom makes sense more than ever but it needs subtle refinement in a society which is almost fed up with information. Only structured knowledge can contribute to a better use of the human resources available. GridSET Exchange makes you take the right direction in your role as  manager or educator.   </paragraph></background> <figure       id="ge2.jpg"      description="The knowledge producer gets a screen for the input of the usual data and additionally for different features, he gets the possibility to use classification scheme terms. Here, you see among others those for Form, Genre, and the Certification scheme. In this case, the information is introduced through a Dutch interface, whereas the knowledge consumer has been using an English interface. Look at Genre in particular."       repository="../../repository" /><product-spec><paragraph>GridSET Exchange features:<unordered-list><list-item>Complete server based system</list-item><list-item>Catalogue with different entrances </list-item><list-item>Defining and analysing research data </list-item><list-item>Tools registering - Inventory </list-item></unordered-list></paragraph></product-spec><system-requirements>GridSET Exchange runs on any operating system with a Java 1.1.8 VM. For some  non-critical features Java 1.2 is needed. GridSET comes packaged wit a web server and Java servlet engine, but can be used with any modern web server and Servlet 2.1 engine.</system-requirements><information><addresses><address><address-line>Austria</address-line><address-line>UMA Information Technology AG</address-line><address-line>Donau City Str 1</address-line><address-line>A-1220 Vienna</address-line><address-line>tel: +43 1 526 2967 701</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@uma.nl</address-line></address><address><address-line>Belgium</address-line><address-line>Space Applications Services</address-line><address-line>Leuvensesteenweg 325</address-line><address-line>B-1932 Zaventem</address-line><address-line>tel: +32 2 7215484</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@spaceapplications.com</address-line></address><address><address-line>The Netherlands</address-line><address-line>Genias Benelux bv</address-line><address-line>James Stewartstraat 248</address-line><address-line>1325 JN Almere</address-line><address-line>tel: +31 36 5373867</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@genias.nl</address-line></address><address><address-line>Greece</address-line><address-line>IDEC S.A.</address-line><address-line>96 Iroon Polytechniou Str.</address-line><address-line>185 36 Piraeus</address-line><address-line>tel: +30 1 04286227</address-line><address-line>mailto: info@idec.gr</address-line></address></addresses></information><date>2002-07-09</date><author>Leslie Versweyveld, Genias</author><editor>Ad Emmen, Genias</editor></factsheet><!-- =============================================================== --><!-- =============================================================== --><factsheet id="f6"><category>Advanced  tools for e-learning</category><title>GridSET Toolkit  for creating 3D simulator based e-learning environments</title><introduction><paragraph>For many training situations, the goal for the student is to acquire knowledge of an item or situation in 3-D. This insight cannot be gathered by looking at pictures or animations. Real-life training is not always possible. The <em>GridSET Toolkit</em> is an integrated set of tools to create 3-D based e-learning environments. You can use the <em>GridSET Toolkit</em> to create training courses for situations where 3-D skills need to be acquired.</paragraph></introduction><background><paragraph>The goal of the <em>GridSET Toolkit</em> is helping you to create training courses that reduce the  time for training of complex procedures.  The <em>GridSET Toolkit</em> has, for instance been used succesfully to create training courses for medical procedures. These procedures require deep knowledge of the exact 3-D composition of a part of the human body.</paragraph><paragraph>It are exactly these two features, allowing training of procedures, and training on 3-D VR-simulators, that make GridSET a unique tool. Furthermore, GridSET can be used over the Internet, making it a useful tool for creating e-learning environments.</paragraph><paragraph>The <em>GridSET Toolkit</em> is not a text-authoring environment. There are other tools available on the market to create that part of your training course. Also you have to create a 3-D simulator. This requires graphic skills. If you do not have these, you can ask the GridSET team for assistance. </paragraph><figure id="demo-63"  /></background><product-spec><paragraph>The <em>GridSET Toolkit</em> is a complete set of tools that you need to set-up an a VR simulator based e-learning environment.It contains:<unordered-list><list-item>Training server to manage  the development and usage of training courses.</list-item><list-item>Sample Simulator module. You have to replace that with one for your specific training needs</list-item><list-item>Conference module, that allows collaboration over the Internet. With virtual classroom features.</list-item><list-item>Procedure module that lets you define a procedure for your training course. It manages thhis procedure during the training later on</list-item><list-item>Evaluation module that allows you to enter criteria that have to be met by students.</list-item><list-item>Annotation module that lets the students and tutors to annotate training courses.</list-item></unordered-list></paragraph><paragraph>If you only incidentally want to use the  <em>GridSET Toolkit</em> it may be worth asking the GridSET Team to help you. We have the skills amongst our partners to rapidly develop any part of the training course, and set-up a working GridSET environment. </paragraph></product-spec><figure id="demo-70"  /><system-requirements>  <paragraph>System requirements: For the server: Windows NT or Unix. For the students (client side): Windows system with Explorer 5.5. All additional software is either packed with the training server, or can be acquired over the web. </paragraph></system-requirements><information><addresses><address><address-line>Austria</address-line><address-line>UMA Information Technology AG</address-line><address-line>Donau City Str 1</address-line><address-line>A-1220 Vienna</address-line><address-line>tel: +43 1 526 2967 701</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@uma.nl</address-line></address><address><address-line>Belgium</address-line><address-line>Space Applications Services</address-line><address-line>Leuvensesteenweg 325</address-line><address-line>B-1932 Zaventem</address-line><address-line>tel: +32 2 7215484</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@spaceapplications.com</address-line></address><address><address-line>The Netherlands</address-line><address-line>Genias Benelux bv</address-line><address-line>James Stewartstraat 248</address-line><address-line>1325 JN Almere</address-line><address-line>tel: +31 36 5373867</address-line><address-line>mailto:info@genias.nl</address-line></address><address><address-line>Greece</address-line><address-line>IDEC S.A.</address-line><address-line>96 Iroon Polytechniou Str.</address-line><address-line>185 36 Piraeus</address-line><address-line>tel: +30 1 04286227</address-line><address-line>mailto: info@idec.gr</address-line></address></addresses></information><date>2002-07-09</date><author>Ad Emmen, Genias</author></factsheet></brochures>